{
  "filename": "2021-2022-HS-History-Bowl-Round-1-A-Set_formattedText.txt",
  "questions": [
    {
      "number": "1.2",
      "quarter": 1,
      "answer": "U.S. penny (or pennies; prompt on \"coins\" until “coin” is mentioned)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "A 2010 redesign of this item removed the initials “VDB” from its front for the secondtime. During World War Two, these items were subject to a discoloring redox reaction whenthe chemistry-unaware Henry Morgenthau [[mohr-GEHN-thow]] authorized the addition ofzinc to them. As a result, one of the most valuable examples of these items is the 1944 “steelwheat” variety. Since 2010 these items display a shield reading “e pluribus unum”. For tenpoints, name these coins which show Abraham Lincoln on the front."
    },
    {
      "number": "1.3",
      "quarter": 1,
      "answer": "Berlin Airlift (accept Operation Vittles; prompt on nonspecific answers)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "During this campaign, a combined 25 American and British planes crashed, with 101fatalities overall. Gail Halvorsen dropped candy to awaiting children during this prolongedcampaign, becoming known as the \"Chocolate Flier\". After the Deutsche [[DOY-chuh]] Markwas introduced, Soviet troops cut off road and rail access to supply an occupied city,immediately causing this event. For ten points, name this aerial campaign led by the UnitedStates to provide aid and supplies to the German capital."
    },
    {
      "number": "1.4",
      "quarter": 1,
      "answer": "Baghdad",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "According to Marco Polo, a ruler of this city was locked in his treasure room withoutfood or water for neglecting to spend his gold on the city’s defense. That ruler of this city, Al-Musta’sim [[al-moo-stah-SEEM]], legendarily died after being rolled in a carpet and trampledto death by an invader’s horses. Harun al-Rashid built a library in this city, which wasdestroyed in a 1258 siege by Hulagu [[hoo-LAH-goo]] Khan. For ten points, name this citywhich contained a “House of Wisdom” before becoming the capital of modern-day Iraq."
    },
    {
      "number": "1.5",
      "quarter": 1,
      "answer": "Denis Diderot [[deh-NEE dih-deh-ROH]]",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Due to his money struggles, this philosopher was offered fifty years pay in advanceby Catherine the Great to serve as her personal librarian. Pope Clement XIII [[the Thirteenth]]banned a compendium written by this man, citing its skepticism of Jesus' miracles. AlongsideJean d'Alembert [[dahl-ehm-BARE]], this man compiled a \"systematic dictionary of thesciences, arts, and crafts\". The chief editor of the Encyclopédie [[ohn-see-cloh-PEH-dee]] was,for ten points, which French philosopher?"
    },
    {
      "number": "1.6",
      "quarter": 1,
      "answer": "The Beatles",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "An early lyric by this group parodies the nativist views of Enoch Powell and demandsthat immigrants return to their “commonwealth homes”. This group's members took an ill-fated trip to Rishikesh [[ree-shee-KESH]] for a guided meditation course with MaharishiMahesh Yogi. A member of this group left that course early to film the documentary Ragaabout his sitar teacher, Ravi Shankar. For ten points, name this influential band of the BritishInvasion whose songs “Get Back” and “Norwegian Wood” were credited to John Lennon andPaul McCartney."
    },
    {
      "number": "1.7",
      "quarter": 1,
      "answer": "HMS Challenger (accept Challenger Deep[/a])",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "For use on this ship, Louis Casella manufactured a resilient version of a Six'sthermometer. Charles W. Thomson supervised the team of naturalists aboard this vessel,whose equipment included over 181 miles of hemp rope. This vessel, commanded by GeorgeNares and Frank Thomson, became the first to measure the depth of an area at the south endof the Mariana Trench. A four-year 1870s oceanographic expedition was undertaken by, forten points, what Royal Navy vessel, after which the deepest point in the Marianas Trench wasnamed?"
    },
    {
      "number": "1.8",
      "quarter": 1,
      "answer": "Opium poppy (accept Opium Wars; accept Opium Triangle; or Opium Crescent;prompt on \"Opiate\")",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "English physician Thomas Sydenham wrote a 17th century manual advocating for aproduct containing this good, laudanum. Soldiers from the Kuomintang organized whatbecame the \"Golden Triangle\" for production of this good while operating in Laos, Thailandand Myanmar. European traders sold this good to circumvent the Canton system, whichexclusively required silver be spent to acquire goods like tea and porcelain. The Qing[[CHING]] and British empires fought two wars named for, for ten points, what illicit druglater used to produce heroin?"
    },
    {
      "number": "1.9",
      "quarter": 1,
      "answer": "Jim Crow Laws (prompt on \"Racial Segregation\" or \"Exclusion\" beforementioned)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Under these laws, a high concrete wall was used to divide off the Eight Mile-WyomingArea. Ferris State University contains a memorabilia museum that houses artifacts related tothese laws, which created a \"ghetto domestic sector\". These laws were almost circumventedin the 1875 Civil Rights Act, which the Supreme Court ruled unconstitutional. Leading to\"colored\" restrooms being a norm, for ten points, what were these racial segregation laws inthe Southern United States?"
    },
    {
      "number": "1.10",
      "quarter": 1,
      "answer": "Neon (accept Ne before mentioned)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "The deflection of this element’s particles led to J. J. Thomson’s discovery of atomicisotopes. It’s not krypton, but British chemist Sir William Ramsay and Morris W. Traversisolated this element in 1898 and named it for the Greek word for “New”. As a byproduct ofair liquefaction, this element was shown by Georges Claude to be able to produce light insealed tubes. For ten points, name this element historically used for signs in Las Vegas."
    },
    {
      "number": "1.11",
      "quarter": 1,
      "answer": "Mississippi River",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "At the behest of Eugene Reybold, a project focused on this river employed a numberof Camp Clinton-housed prisoners from the German Afrika Korps. A series of levees were builtalong this river in the aftermath of an event that bolstered Huey Long’s gubernatorialcampaign and resulted in Herbert Hoover leading a series of relief operations. That piece oflegislation also mandated the creation of the Birds Point-New Madrid Floodway along thisriver. For ten points, name this major American river that experienced a “great” 1927 flood."
    },
    {
      "number": "2.1",
      "quarter": 2,
      "answer": "Giuseppe Garibaldi (or Giuseppe Maria Garibaldi)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Working with General David Canaberro, this general established the Juliana Republicin southern Brazil. This man was infuriated by an agreement made at Plombières [[plohm-BEE-air]], which promised to cede his home city of Nice to France. This leader of the \"Huntersof the Alps\" aligned with the Colorados during the Uruguayan Civil War, after which hereturned to his home country to lead the Expedition of the Thousand to Sicily. For ten points,name this Italian general, considered a father of the First Italian Republic."
    },
    {
      "number": "2.1.B",
      "quarter": 2,
      "answer": "Camillo Benso, Count of Cavour (accept either underlined answer; acceptCamillo Paolo Filippo Giulio Benso, Count of Cavour, Isolabella and Leri)",
      "is_bonus": true,
      "question": "Which Italian statesman, who reluctantly negotiated the cessation of Savoy to Francein the Treaty of Plombières, became the first prime minister of Italy?"
    },
    {
      "number": "2.2",
      "quarter": 2,
      "answer": "Aaron Copland [[KOHP-land]]",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "The fanfare Buckaroo Holiday begins a ballet by this composer, whose choreographer,Agnes de Mille, later worked on the thematically similar Oklahoma! . Martha Graham earneda Pulitzer Prize for her work with this composer for a piece which celebrates the Americanpioneer and includes a reworking of the Shaker hymn \"Simple Gifts\". Rodeo, Fanfare for theCommon Man, and Appalachian Spring were written by, for ten points, which Americancomposer?"
    },
    {
      "number": "2.2.B",
      "quarter": 2,
      "answer": "Billy the Kid (accept William Bonney)",
      "is_bonus": true,
      "question": "Copland composed a work named for which outlaw who was gunned down by PatGarrett in 1881?"
    },
    {
      "number": "2.3",
      "quarter": 2,
      "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci (accept either underlined portion)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "For years, scholars suspected that several frescoes in the Hall of the Five Hundred atthe Palazzo Vecchio were painted over this man's historical work, The Battle of Anghiari. Under the patronage of Ludovico Sforza, this man developed a design for a \"turtle-shell\"fighting vehicle as well as a self-propelled cart and an automaton, though most of his workwent unpublished due to being written in a secretive mirror script. For ten points, name thispainter and inventor who is considered the consummate \"Renaissance Man\"."
    },
    {
      "number": "2.3.B",
      "quarter": 2,
      "answer": "Crossbow (accept Genoese Crossbowmen; do not accept \"Bow and Arrow\")",
      "is_bonus": true,
      "question": "Leonardo's Codex Atlanticus contains a design for a \"rapid-fire\" example of thisweapon, which was notably wielded by an internationally-recruited medieval mercenaryforce from Genoa."
    },
    {
      "number": "2.4",
      "quarter": 2,
      "answer": "Louisiana Purchase",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "This acquisition was retroactively confirmed by the decision American Insurance Co.v. Canter. Secretary of the Treasury Albert Gallatin informed the sitting president that thisacquisition was protected by the treaty-making provision in the Constitution. The costlinessof the Haitian revolution led to this sale of territory by Napoleon to the United States. TheJefferson administration facilitated, for ten points, what \"Purchase\" which doubled the sizeof the United States?"
    },
    {
      "number": "2.4.B",
      "quarter": 2,
      "answer": "Lewis and Clark (or Merriweather Lewis and William Clark; accept in eitherorder)",
      "is_bonus": true,
      "question": "The territory of the Louisiana Purchase was explored by which duo of officers wholed the Corps of Discovery?"
    },
    {
      "number": "2.5",
      "quarter": 2,
      "answer": "Electric Car (accept Electric vehicle; accept descriptive answers about carsrunning on a lithium-ion battery or cars running on electricity; prompt on \"Car\")",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "An invention produced by Andreas Flocken is often considered the first \"true\" one ofthese objects, which were also produced by Walter Bersey in London. The development ofMOSFET helped spark the modern commercial interest in these objects, whose first mass-produced example was the Roadster. Initially eclipsed by the emergence of internal-combustion engine vehicles, for ten points, what are these vehicles run entirely withoutgasoline, including the popular Tesla Model 3?"
    },
    {
      "number": "2.5.B",
      "quarter": 2,
      "answer": "Bonneville Salt Flats (accept Bonneville Speedway)",
      "is_bonus": true,
      "question": "The first six land-speed records were broken by electric vehicles, primarily in France,though for several decades the record was broken by gasoline-powered cars at what recently-deteriorated site in Utah?"
    },
    {
      "number": "2.6",
      "quarter": 2,
      "answer": "Kingdom of Egypt (accept Aegypttos; accept Kemet)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Successful commanders from this kingdom were often equated to the god Montu, awar deity who takes the shape of a bull. This polity employed the Medjay, a distinct Cushiticspeaking people who served as a paramilitary police force. This kingdom created the sickleshaped sword meant for close-combat known as the Khopesh, and its military mass-adoptedthe chariot after being invaded by the Hyksos [[HIK-sohs]]. For ten points, name this ancientAfrican kingdom which fought at the Battles of Megiddo and the Nile Delta."
    },
    {
      "number": "2.6.B",
      "quarter": 2,
      "answer": "Canaan (accept Kenaʿn; accept Canaanites)",
      "is_bonus": true,
      "question": "The invading Hyksos were likely from what Levantine region? The Biblical PromisedLand corresponds to this region, which included Philistia and Phoenicia."
    },
    {
      "number": "2.7",
      "quarter": 2,
      "answer": "Syracuse (accept Syracusa; or Sarausa; or Syracusae)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "A tyrant of this city named Dionysius the Elder arrested the philosopher Plato andsold him into slavery following a disagreement. A former general of Pyrrhus of Epirus, HieroII, served as a tyrant of this city, becoming a client of Rome during the First Punic War. Archimedes allegedly used a parabolic reflector to defend this city from a Roman attack,inventing the first \"heat ray\". For ten points, name this ancient Greek colony in the southeastof Sicily."
    },
    {
      "number": "2.7.B",
      "quarter": 2,
      "answer": "Corinth (or Korinthos)",
      "is_bonus": true,
      "question": "The first settlers to Syracuse were from which Greek city-state which shares its namewith an isthmus that connects Attica and the Peloponnese?"
    },
    {
      "number": "2.8",
      "quarter": 2,
      "answer": "Chicago",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "A subset of the \"Great Railroad Strike of 1877\" in this city included strikers trappingpolice officers on the Halsted Street bridge in the Battle of the Viaduct. During the \"RedSummer,\" this city suffered a race riot on its South Side after African-American teen EugeneWilliams was killed for swimming near an \"All-White\" beach. This city's Hyde Parkneighborhood hosted the Columbian Exposition of 1893. Hull House was founded in, for tenpoints, which Midwestern city that suffered a \"Great Fire\" in the 1870s?"
    },
    {
      "number": "2.8.B",
      "quarter": 2,
      "answer": "Irish-Americans",
      "is_bonus": true,
      "question": "Contributing to the violence of the Chicago Race Riot, the Hamburg Athletic Club,which included future mayor Richard J. Daley, was composed primarily of what whiteimmigrant ethnic group that fiercely guarded neighborhoods like Bridgeport and Back of theYards."
    },
    {
      "number": "3.1",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Portland",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Largest city in Oregon whose founder named it for his home city in Maine."
    },
    {
      "number": "3.2",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Salem",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Capital city possibly named for a site of witch trials in Massachusetts."
    },
    {
      "number": "3.3",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Columbia River",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "River on which the Grand Coulee Dam was built during the Great Depression."
    },
    {
      "number": "3.4",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Mount Saint Helens",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Mountain whose disastrous 1980 eruption covered parts of Washington and Oregonin ash."
    },
    {
      "number": "3.5",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "James Cook",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Explorer who was the first European to discover Hawaii and who later mappedparts of the Oregon coast."
    },
    {
      "number": "3.6",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "John Jacob Astor (accept Astoria)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "First American millionaire whose Pacific Fur Company founded a namesakesettlement in Oregon."
    },
    {
      "number": "3.7",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Chinook (or Tsinuk; accept Boeing CH-47 Chinook)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Indigenous people who practiced headbinding, now known for being the namesakeof a U.S. Army transport helicopter."
    },
    {
      "number": "3.8",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Cockstock Incident2021-22 A Set History Bowl - 2021-09-23 Round 1The Iron CurtainConcerning the ideological divi",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "1840s \"incident\" where a black man killed a Casco native over a horse, leading topassage of Oregon's anti-Black settlement laws."
    },
    {
      "number": "3.9",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Warsaw (accept Warsaw Pact)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Polish capital which names a \"Pact\" of Communist nations led by the Soviet Union."
    },
    {
      "number": "3.10",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Winston Churchill (or Winston Leonard Spencer Churchill)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "British prime minister who coined the term \"Iron Curtain\" in a 1946 speech."
    },
    {
      "number": "3.11",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "North Atlantic Treaty Organization (accept NATO)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "1949 Collective Security organization including most Western European nations andthe United States."
    },
    {
      "number": "3.12",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Yalta Conference (accept Argonaut)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Conference in Crimea where the Allies agreed on how to split Europe."
    },
    {
      "number": "3.13",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Non-Aligned Movement (accept NAM)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "\"Movement\" advocated by the likes of Kwame Nkrumah and Josip Tito as analternative to the Eastern and Western blocs."
    },
    {
      "number": "3.14",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "People's Socialist Republic of Albania (or Republika Popullore Socialiste eShqipërisë)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Nation whose dictator Enver Hoxha [[HOH-shah]] re-aligned his state from the USSRto Communist China in the 1960s."
    },
    {
      "number": "3.15",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Erich Honecker (or Erich Ernst Paul Honecker)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "East German prime minister whose forced resignation in 1989 paved the way for aunified Germany."
    },
    {
      "number": "3.16",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Sinatra Doctrine2021-22 A Set History Bowl - 2021-09-23 Round 1Aparth",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "\"Doctrine\" named for an American singer which Mikhail Gorbachev adopted,allowing neighbors to deal with their own internal affairs."
    },
    {
      "number": "3.17",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Republic of South Africa (or RSA)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Country where Daniel Malan formalized apartheid in 1948?"
    },
    {
      "number": "3.18",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Nelson Mandela (or Nelson Rolihlahla Mandela)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Longtime prisoner who negotiated an end to apartheid with F.W. de Klerk beforebecoming president?"
    },
    {
      "number": "3.19",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "1990s",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Decade in which apartheid was dismantled and multiracial elections first tookplace?"
    },
    {
      "number": "3.20",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Sharpeville Massacre",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "1960 incident in which police killed 69 anti-passbook protestors?"
    },
    {
      "number": "3.21",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Rugby (union)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Popular English sport played on the controversial \"Springbok tour\" in 1981?"
    },
    {
      "number": "3.22",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Bantustans",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Common name for the Black \"homelands\" granted sham independence starting in1972?"
    },
    {
      "number": "3.23",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Sun City",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Resort that named a 1985 pro-boycott song composed by Steven Van Zandt?"
    },
    {
      "number": "3.24",
      "quarter": 3,
      "answer": "Steve Biko (or Bantu Stephen Biko)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Leader of the Black Consciousness Movement who died in police custody in 1977?"
    },
    {
      "number": "4.2",
      "quarter": 4,
      "answer": "NBC (or National Broadcasting Company)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "In 1937, this organization became the namesake of an orchestra conducted byArturo Toscanini that transformed into the Symphony of the Air in 1954. Thisorganization hired Peter Adler to conduct a namesake Opera Theatre that premieredAmahl and (+) the Night Visitors in 1951. Doc Severinsen, Max Weinberg, and KevinEubanks have led in-house bands on this company's late-night (*) shows. For ten points,name this radio and TV network which trademarked the three-chime sequence that playsover its peacock logo."
    },
    {
      "number": "4.3",
      "quarter": 4,
      "answer": "Eugène Delacroix (or Ferdinand Victor Eugène Delacroix)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "A tableau by this artist depicts the historical Battle of Taillebourg [[TIE-bur]]during the Saintonge [[sahn-TAHNG]] War. While an attaché to a diplomatic envoy tothe Kingdom of (+) Morocco, this artist painted the Orientalist work Women of Algiers. The toppling of Charles X [[the Tenth]] is represented by this artist in a paintingdepicting a bare-breasted women carrying the tricolour [[tree-koh-LOHR]] flag ofFrance. Liberty (*) Leading the People was painted by, for ten points, which French Romanticartist?"
    },
    {
      "number": "4.4",
      "quarter": 4,
      "answer": "Massachusetts",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "In the 2020 senate election in this U.S. state, a conspiracy theorist who claimsto have invented e-mail, Shiva Ayyadurai, was defeated in the Republican primary. Thekidnapping of Colin Bower's children and the police killing of DJ (+) Henry becameissues in this state's Democratic primary, which determined who would faceRepublican nominee Kevin O'Connor. A congressman from a political dynasty in thisstate lost the primary to incumbent Ed (*) Markey. For ten points, name this state fromwhich Markey continues to serve as senator alongside Elizabeth Warren."
    },
    {
      "number": "4.5",
      "quarter": 4,
      "answer": "Ho Chi Minh (or Nguyễn Sinh Cung)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "This non-Chinese figure trained at the Whampoa Military Academy and offeredDavid Ben-Gurion and the Jewish people a homeland in his nation. This politician usedthe pseudonym \"Nguyen [[WHEN]] the (+) Patriot\" while writing articles prior to theVersailles Peace Talks. This man led the 1945 August General Uprising whichsuccessfully deposed the colonial French following the nine-year First (*) IndochinaWar. The city of Saigon was renamed in honor of, for ten points, which first president ofcommunist Vietnam?"
    },
    {
      "number": "4.6",
      "quarter": 4,
      "answer": "George Wallace (accept George Corley Wallace Jr.)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "In this man’s final run for office, he defeated mayor Emory Folmar afternarrowly winning the Democratic primary against Lieutenant Governor GeorgeMcMillan. During one of his four runs for president, this man survived an assassinationattempt which left him paralyzed (+) below the waist. This man briefly served as FirstGentleman after his wife, Lurleen, became (*) Alabama’s first female governor. For tenpoints, name this long-time Alabama politician who once declared “segregation now,segregation tomorrow, segregation forever”."
    },
    {
      "number": "4.7",
      "quarter": 4,
      "answer": "Myanmar (accept Republic of the Union of Myanmar; or Pyidaunzu ThanmădaMyăma Nainngandaw; accept Burma before mentioned)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Soe Naing was the first of over a hundred journalists from this nation to beimprisoned in 2021, with many being placed in the Insein Prison first run by the StateLaw and Order (+) Restoration Council. 2020 election results in this nation wereannulled following a coup by the Tatmadaw [[taht-MAH-\"tau\"]] armed forces. Thatcoup removed Aung (*) San Suu Kyi [[CHEE]] from power in, for ten points, which southeastAsian nation, once known as Burma?"
    },
    {
      "number": "4.8",
      "quarter": 4,
      "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt Jr. (or Teddy [a]Roosevelt; prompt on \"Roosevelt\" or \"T.R.\")",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "This man compared the extinction of civilization to that of a species in his 1910Romanes lecture Biological Analogies in History. A late 1880s winter killed much of thisman's cattle, forcing him to abandon his ranching venture at Elkhorn. With his son, (+)Kermit, this man headed a namesake expedition with the Smithsonian, collecting over11,000 animal specimens and authoring African Game Trails. (*) For ten points, namethis U.S. president, whose saving of a cub led to the creation of his namesake stuffed bear."
    },
    {
      "number": "4.9",
      "quarter": 4,
      "answer": "King John (accept John Lackland)",
      "is_bonus": false,
      "question": "Medieval historian Roger of Wendover claimed that this man offered to convertto Islam if Muhammad al-Nasir lent him military support. This man's refusal to appointsub-prior Reginald to the post of Archbishop of (+) Canterbury led to his temporaryexcommunication by Innocent III. This king was temporarily deposed by the FrenchKing, Louis the Lion, after he captured half of England during the First (*) Barons' War. For ten points, name this brother of Richard the Lionheart and signer of the Magna Carta."
    }
  ],
  "categories": ["Oregon", "The Iron Curtain", "Apartheid"]
}